SEYDOU COULIBALY

Python Software Engineer

- @ seydou.coulibaly.ing@gmail.com
- **J** +33 768 189 787
- Clermont-Ferrand, France

- in seydoucoulibaly
- seydou-coulibaly
- seydou-coulibaly.github.io

STRENGTHS





Docker Agile methodology

Tests Debugger CI/CD

Curious Motivated

Fast learner | Autonomous

Modelisation

LEARNING

Arabe Data science

Devops methodology

LANGUAGES

Bambara: Native English: Proficient French: Mastery

REFERENCES

François Treyve - Dexade Bernardetta ADDIS - Loria Inga Girardin - Sayens Sébastien LANNEZ - Fico

ABOUT ME

Craftsman of modern times, I develop applications in various environments. Through my degree in operations research and professional experiences, I acquired a good understanding of algorithms, their efficiencies and the ability to modelize or solve real decisions problems. I have interest for data science and devops methodology.

EXPERIENCE

Python Software Engineer | Dexade

10 2021 - In progress

- Clermont-Ferrand, France
- Consultant for the tire physics simulation department at Michelin
- Processing of the resulted files of the finite element method's solver
- · Restitution of simulation indicator to tire designer
- Data processing

Python Software Engineer | Satt Sayens - innovation catalyst

= 09 2019 - 05 2021

- Nancy, France
- Development of a decision support library to assist process engineers
- Add Visualisation component of the resulted decision solution
- A ready to use prototype from research paper thesis

Optimization Engineer Intern | Fair Isaac Corporation - FICO

1 02 2019 - 08 2019

- Tours, France
- Literature review on Multiobjective optimization of mixed-integer linear problems
- participation in the development of a multi-objective decision support prototype
- Work in an agile environment with an international team

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Science, | Nantes Université

= 09 2016 - 09 2019

- Nantes, France
- Optimization in Operations Research specialist
- with high honours

Master's first year in computer science | Université Grenoble Alpes

= 09 2015 - 08 2016

Grenoble, France

with standard pass

Licence's degree in computer science | Djillali Liabes University

10 2012 - 08 2015

- Sidi Bel Abbes, Algeria
- Cisco Networking Academy (CCNA I)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate, Routing Protocols And Concepts (CCNA2)
- with high honours